<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workspace Administration and User Guide on</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/</link><description>Recent content in Workspace Administration and User Guide on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Workspace Overview</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/what-is-workspace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/what-is-workspace/</guid><description>&lt;p>A workspace is a logical unit to organize your &lt;a href="../../project-administration/">projects&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="../../devops-user-guide/">DevOps projects&lt;/a> and manage &lt;a href="../upload-helm-based-application/">app templates&lt;/a> and app repositories. It is the place for you to control resource access and share resources within your team in a secure way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is a best practice to create a new workspace for tenants (excluding cluster administrators). A same tenant can work in multiple workspaces, while a workspace allows multiple tenants to access it in different ways.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upload Helm-based Applications</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/upload-helm-based-application/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/upload-helm-based-application/</guid><description>&lt;p>KubeSphere provides full lifecycle management for applications. Among other things, workspace administrators can upload or create new app templates and test them quickly. Furthermore, they publish well-tested apps to the &lt;a href="../../application-store/">App Store&lt;/a> so that other users can deploy them with one click. To develop app templates, workspace administrators need to upload packaged &lt;a href="https://helm.sh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Helm charts&lt;/a> to KubeSphere first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This tutorial demonstrates how to develop an app template by uploading a packaged Helm chart.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Workspace Role and Member Management</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/role-and-member-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/role-and-member-management/</guid><description>&lt;p>This tutorial demonstrates how to manage roles and members in a workspace.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At least one workspace has been created, such as &lt;code>demo-workspace&lt;/code>. Besides, you need a user of the &lt;code>workspace-admin&lt;/code> role (for example, &lt;code>ws-admin&lt;/code>) at the workspace level. For more information, see &lt;a href="../../quick-start/create-workspace-and-project/">Create Workspaces, Projects, Users and Roles&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="notices note">
 
 &lt;p>Note&lt;/p>
 &lt;div>The actual role name follows a naming convention: &lt;code>workspace name-role name&lt;/code>. For example, for a workspace named &lt;code>demo-workspace&lt;/code>, the actual role name of the role &lt;code>admin&lt;/code> is &lt;code>demo-workspace-admin&lt;/code>.&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="built-in-roles">Built-in Roles&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In &lt;strong>Workspace Roles&lt;/strong>, there are four available built-in roles. Built-in roles are created automatically by KubeSphere when a workspace is created and they cannot be edited or deleted. You can only view permissions included in a built-in role or assign it to a user.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Workspace Network Isolation</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/workspace-network-isolation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/workspace-network-isolation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>You have already enabled &lt;a href="../../pluggable-components/network-policy/">Network Policies&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Use a user of the &lt;code>workspace-admin&lt;/code> role. For example, use the &lt;code>ws-admin&lt;/code> user created in &lt;a href="../../quick-start/create-workspace-and-project/">Create Workspaces, Projects, Users and Roles&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="notices note">
 
 &lt;p>Note&lt;/p>
 &lt;div>For the implementation of the network policy, you can refer to &lt;a href="https://github.com/kubesphere/community/blob/master/sig-network/concepts-and-designs/kubesphere-network-policy.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KubeSphere NetworkPolicy&lt;/a>.&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="enable-or-disable-workspace-network-isolation">Enable or Disable Workspace Network Isolation&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Workspace network isolation is disabled by default. You can turn on network isolation in &lt;strong>Basic Information&lt;/strong> under &lt;strong>Workspace Settings&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="notices note">
 
 &lt;p>Note&lt;/p>
 &lt;div>When network isolation is turned on, egress traffic will be allowed by default, while ingress traffic will be denied for different workspaces. If you need to customize your network policy, you need to turn on &lt;a href="../../project-administration/project-network-isolation/">Project Network Isolation&lt;/a> and add a network policy in &lt;strong>Project Settings&lt;/strong>.&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>You can also disable network isolation on the &lt;strong>Basic Information&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project Quotas</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/project-quotas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/project-quotas/</guid><description>&lt;p>KubeSphere uses &lt;a href="https://kubesphere.io/blogs/understand-requests-and-limits-in-kubernetes/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes requests and limits&lt;/a> to control resource (for example, CPU and memory) usage in a project, also known as &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/policy/resource-quotas/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">resource quotas&lt;/a> in Kubernetes. Requests make sure a project can get the resources it needs as they are specifically guaranteed and reserved. On the contrary, limits ensure that a project can never use resources above a certain value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Besides CPU and memory, you can also set resource quotas for other objects separately such as Pods, &lt;a href="../../project-user-guide/application-workloads/deployments/">Deployments&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="../../project-user-guide/application-workloads/jobs/">Jobs&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="../../project-user-guide/application-workloads/services/">Services&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="../../project-user-guide/configuration/configmaps/">ConfigMaps&lt;/a> in a project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Workspace Quotas</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/workspace-quotas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/workspace-quotas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Workspace quotas are used to control the total resource usage of all projects and DevOps projects in a workspace. Similar to &lt;a href="../project-quotas/">project quotas&lt;/a>, workspace quotas contain requests and limits of CPU and memory. Requests make sure projects in the workspace can get the resources they needs as they are specifically guaranteed and reserved. On the contrary, limits ensure that the resource usage of all projects in the workspace can never go above a certain value.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Department Management</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/department-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/workspace-administration/department-management/</guid><description>&lt;p>This document describes how to manage workspace departments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A department in a workspace is a logical unit used for permission control. You can set a workspace role, multiple project roles, and multiple DevOps project roles in a department, and assign users to the department to control user permissions in batches.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You need to &lt;a href="../../quick-start/create-workspace-and-project/">create a workspace and a user&lt;/a> assigned the &lt;code>workspace-admin&lt;/code> role in the workspace. This document uses the &lt;code>demo-ws&lt;/code> workspace and the &lt;code>ws-admin&lt;/code> account as an example.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To set project roles or DevOps project roles in a department, you need to &lt;a href="../../quick-start/create-workspace-and-project/">create at least one project or DevOps project&lt;/a> in the workspace.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="create-a-department">Create a Department&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Log in to the KubeSphere web console as &lt;code>ws-admin&lt;/code> and go to the &lt;code>demo-ws&lt;/code> workspace.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>