<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>news on</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/</link><description>Recent content in news on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://openksc.github.io/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Announcing KubeSphere 3.1.0 on AWS Quick Start!</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-310-on-aws-quick-start/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-310-on-aws-quick-start/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://openksc.github.io/images/news/aws-quick-start/kubesphere-aws.png" alt="kubecon-eu-banner">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-aws-quick-start">What is AWS Quick Start&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/quickstart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS Quick Starts&lt;/a> are automated reference deployments that use AWS CloudFormation templates to deploy key technologies on Amazon Web Services (AWS) and follow AWS best practices.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="out-of-the-box-integration-with-amazon-eks">Out of the box integration with Amazon EKS&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In January 2021, KubeSphere Team and AWS have collaborated to make it easy to create the KubeSphere and Amazon EKS on AWS, and announced &lt;a href="https://kubesphere.io/news/kubesphere-available-on-aws-quickstart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">their partnership to offer KubeSphere&lt;/a>, a distributed operating system born for managing cloud-native apps across clouds and data center, as an &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/quickstart/architecture/qingcloud-kubesphere/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AWS Quick Start&lt;/a>. KubeSphere Quick Start uses AWS CloudFormation templates to help customers automatically provision an Amazon EKS cluster on the AWS Cloud. Customers can easily manage Amazon EKS clusters through the KubeSphere console.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Embrace KubeSphere Spanish Community and European Market: Geko and KubeSphere Build Partnership</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-geko-partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-geko-partnership/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://pek3b.qingstor.com/kubesphere-docs/png/20200725081853.png" alt="Geko and KubeSphere Build Partnership">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>July 22, 2020 - KubeSphere and Geko are pleased to announce a joint partnership to deliver outstanding value to KubeSphere users in Spain, and further to Europe. As part of KubeSphere’s endeavor to bring the fruitful result of open source to users around the world, this marks a great milestone for the container platform as we are embracing a more diversified and vibrant community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spain is home to one of the most active open source communities in Europe. KubeCon and CloudNativeCon have also been hosted in Barcelona for many times. Besides, Spain is also a popular gathering place for cloud native enthusiasts. Geko, a strong and active player in the cloud industry of Spain, offers state-of-the-art technologies that help companies with cloud adoption, hybrid computing, container artifact development, and DevOps. In this connection, Geko has made great contribution to cloud native technologies, which echoes KubeSphere’s commitment to open source, with a shared aspiration to benefit everyone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Explore CNCF KCD Turkey with KubeSphere Turkey</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/explore-cncf-kcd-turkey-with-kubesphere-turkey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/explore-cncf-kcd-turkey-with-kubesphere-turkey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Witness the power of collaboration: KubeSphere Turkey and Community worked together for KCD Turkey!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="kcd-turkey">KCD Turkey&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://pek3b.qingstor.com/kubesphere-community/images/kcd-turkey-cover.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KCD Turkey was an extraordinary 3-day onsite event designed exclusively for tech enthusiasts and professionals passionate about Kubernetes and cloud technologies. From June 13th to June 15th, 2023, KCD Turkey worked with KubeSphere Turkey to bring an immersive and unforgettable experience that would revolutionize your understanding of the tech landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Attracting a diverse community of 570 attendees, KCD Turkey is the premier gathering for cutting-edge knowledge and networking opportunities. This dynamic event caters to 50 students, 50 sponsor invitees, and 470 ticketed participants, ensuring a vibrant mix of industry pioneers, aspiring talents, and key influencers. Additionally, 12 sponsors offered various gifts and opportunities have enhanced the overall experience for attendees, providing them with additional insights and networking prospects.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Extending Kubernetes to Edge: KubeSphere Container Platform 3.1 General Availability</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.1.0-ga-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.1.0-ga-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>On April 29, 2021, the KubeSphere community was excited to announce the general availability of KubeSphere v3.1.0. KubeSphere, as an app-centric distributed operating system running on top of Kubernetes, has further expanded its portfolio to deliver more robust experiences for users across the globe. This has once again echoed our commitment: enabling our users to run Kubernetes workloads where and when they want with ease and security.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KubeSphere v3.1.0 looks to provide an enabling environment for users &lt;strong>as they deploy production workloads not just across clouds but also at the edge&lt;/strong>. Besides, the new &lt;strong>Metering and Billing&lt;/strong> function helps you better understand infrastructure operating costs. Existing features of &lt;strong>multi-cluster management&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>multi-tenant management&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>observability&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>DevOps&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>application lifecycle management&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>microservices governance&lt;/strong> have also been enhanced as we work to ensure better user experiences &lt;strong>across clusters and clouds&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hiring: KubeSphere Dev Advocate</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/hiring-kubesphere-dev-advocate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/hiring-kubesphere-dev-advocate/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Job Title: Developer Advocate (Remote, Full-time/Part-time)&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Location:&lt;/strong> Remote, India&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Company:&lt;/strong> KubeSphere(QingCloud Technology. Inc.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>About KubeSphere:&lt;/strong>
KubeSphere is a leading open-source container platform that simplifies Kubernetes and cloud-native operations. We are expanding our team in India and looking for a passionate Developer Advocate to promote our latest innovative LuBan architecture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Job Description:&lt;/strong>
As a Developer Advocate at KubeSphere, your primary role will be to enhance our brand presence and boost user engagement through effective content marketing strategies. You will be the bridge between KubeSphere and the broader developer community, helping to spread the word about our new LuBan architecture and driving its adoption.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeCon and CloudNativeCon Europe 2021 is coming! Welcome to join us!</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/join-us-at-kubecon-eu-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/join-us-at-kubecon-eu-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction-to-kubecon-and-cloudnativecon-europe-2021">Introduction to KubeCon and CloudNativeCon Europe 2021&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://openksc.github.io/images/news/kubecon-eu/kubecon-news-banner.png" alt="kubecon-eu-banner">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/kubecon-cloudnativecon-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">KubeCon and CloudNativeCon Europe 2021&lt;/a>, the Cloud Native Computing Foundation’s flagship conference, gathers adopters and technologists from leading open source and cloud-native communities virtually from May 4 – 7, 2021.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Invited by the Data on Kubernetes Community, the KubeSphere Community is excited to announce that we will be present at the Data on Kubernetes Day and give a speech about the KubeSphere Container Platform.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Community Days China Recap</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubernetes-community-days-china/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubernetes-community-days-china/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="kubernetes-community-days-china">Kubernetes Community Days China&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://openksc.github.io/images/news/kcd-china/kcd-china-event.png" alt="kcd-china-event">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://community.cncf.io/kubernetes-community-days/about-kcd/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kubernetes Community Days (KCD)&lt;/a> was initiated by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation (CNCF) and is jointly organized by local CNCF ambassadors, CNCF employees, and CNCF members across the world. KCD is currently being actively organized worldwide, gathering end users, contributors, and technical experts from the open-source community in the cloud-native field. This series of localized activities will help grow the Kubernetes Community and spread cloud-native technology more widely among end-users in different industries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere 2021 Year in Review</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-2021-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-2021-year-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 2021, we have witnessed emerging cloud-native technologies, technological innovations, and the power of the open source community. We have also accomplished a lot of milestones with the collaboration of all users, contributors, and partners.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let's take a look back at the milestones and story of the KubeSphere community over the past year and appreciate all the members who have contributed to the KubeSphere community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://openksc.github.io/images/news/community-report-2021/2021-community-recap.png" alt="KubeSphere Community Report 2021">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-state-of-projects-under-the-kubesphere-umbrella">The state of projects under the KubeSphere umbrella&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Over the past 3 years, the KubeSphere community has spawned many new open source projects centered around KubeSphere, such as KubeKey, OpenELB, and OpenFunction, all of which have been widely used by users worldwide. They can be integrated into KubeSphere not only as addons, but also as standalone projects used with Kubernetes. These projects have joined the CNCF Landscape, contributing to the prosperity of the cloud-native ecosystem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere 2022 Year in Review</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-2022-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-2022-year-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 2022, we've witnessed cloud native technology shifts from boom to mature, and an increasing number of projects with tech inche start emerging and provide backbone for cloud native apps in full lifecycle. Technology such as infrastructure as code (IaC), microservices, and serverless architecture automates provisioning and makes infrastructure resources flexible. At the same time, the development of open source tends to go stable after reaching a saturation point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All together, our KubeSphere open source community has also found its stride and grown at a constant pace.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere 2023 Year in Review</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-2023-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-2023-year-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>As we bid farewell to 2023, let's reflect on the developments within the KubeSphere open-source community throughout the year. This article serves as a heartfelt appreciation to all the contributors who dedicated their efforts to the KubeSphere community in 2023. Check it out to see if your name is among those recognized!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="developments-of-kubesphere-projects">Developments of KubeSphere Projects&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In 2023, with the participation of contributors from China and international communities, KubeSphere and the open-source projects derived from the KubeSphere community have made steady and active progress. All the contributors are appreciated!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere 2024 Year in Review</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-2024-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-2024-year-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>As 2024 comes to a close, we reflect on every step the KubeSphere community has taken this year with much appreciation. In 2024, KubeSphere continued to lead the innovation and development of cloud-native technologies, promote the spread of open-source culture, and strive to provide more powerful platforms and solutions for global developers and enterprise users. We are grateful to every community member for their hard work. It is thanks to your collective efforts that KubeSphere has been able to grow and thrive, becoming a core force in global cloud-native technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere 3.0.0 GA: Born for Hybrid Cloud Apps</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.0.0-ga-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.0.0-ga-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>August 31, 2020 - KubeSphere open source community today announces the General Availability of KubeSphere 3.0.0!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KubeSphere 3.0.0 highlights key features for hybrid clouds. It is born for &lt;strong>multi-cloud operation, multi-cluster deployment, multi-team cooperation and multi-tenant management&lt;/strong>, boasting powerful enhancements for &lt;strong>cluster management, observability, storage and network management, multi-tenant security, App Store, installation and more&lt;/strong>. It provides better user experiences as it becomes more interactive and responsive. KubeSphere 3.0.0 is by far the most important version ever released. As a unified control plane for multiple clouds and clusters, KubeSphere 3.0.0 will further drive enterprises forward as they implement their &lt;strong>multi-cloud and hybrid cloud strategies&lt;/strong>. It greatly lowers the threshold for enterprises to operate and maintain Kubernetes clusters across any infrastructure. This is how KubeSphere works to achieve rapid delivery of modern applications in containerized environments. As a result, enterprises can greatly benefit from the &lt;strong>holistic platform-level solution&lt;/strong> provided by KubeSphere to build cloud-native stacks in production.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere 3.2.0 GA: Bringing AI-oriented GPU Scheduling and Flexible Gateway</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.2.0-ga-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.2.0-ga-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://openksc.github.io/images/blogs/en/release-announcement3.2.0/3.2.0GA.png" alt="3.2.0GA">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No one would ever doubt that &lt;strong>Cloud Native&lt;/strong> has become the most popular service technology. KubeSphere, a distributed operating system for cloud-native application management with Kubernetes as its kernel, is definitely one of the tide riders surfing the cloud-native currents. KubeSphere has always been upholding the commitment of 100% open source. Owing to support from the open-source community, KubeSphere has rapidly established a worldwide presence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On November 2, 2021, we are excited to announce KubeSphere 3.2.0 is generally available!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere 3.3.1 is now generally available</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.3.1-ga-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.3.1-ga-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since the first release four years ago, KubeSphere has witnessed more than 10 iterations. Today, we're excited to announce that our open-source KubeSphere project has attracted over &lt;strong>320&lt;/strong> contributors, and the main repository of KubeSphere has reached over &lt;strong>11300&lt;/strong> GitHub stars and &lt;strong>1700&lt;/strong> forks, with millions of downloads worldwide to date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ever since the release of KubeSphere 3.3.0 in &lt;strong>June&lt;/strong> of this year, our community members have been awaiting the next official release. Finally, it's today that KubeSphere 3.3.1 gets officially released!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere 3.4.0 Released: Support K8s v1.26</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.4.0-ga-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.4.0-ga-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>On July 26, 2023, KubeSphere 3.4.0 is officially released!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let's briefly review the major changes in the previous three releases:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>KubeSphere 3.1.0 introduced new features such as &amp;quot;Edge Computing&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Metering and Billing,&amp;quot; expanding Kubernetes from the cloud to the edge.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>KubeSphere 3.2.0 added support for &amp;quot;GPU Resource Scheduling and Management&amp;quot; and GPU usage monitoring, further enhancing the user experience in cloud-native AI scenarios.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>KubeSphere 3.3.0 added a continuous deployment solution based on GitOps, further optimizing the user experience of DevOps.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>KubeSphere 3.4.0 has officially released, bringing noteworthy new features and enhancements. Here are some highlights:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere 3.4.1 Released: fixed bugs</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.4.1-ga-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.4.1-ga-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are pleased to announce the official release of KubeSphere 3.4.1!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release was made possible by 15 contributors and we thank you for your support and contributions to the KubeSphere project!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KubeSphere 3.4.1 is a patch to KubeSphere 3.4.0, focusing on Console and DevOps enhancements and fixes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="console">Console&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix inaccurate Chinese translations in some page fields.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue on the project overview page where help information is missing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue on the list page where the custom content button displays incomplete content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of resource creation failing in higher versions of Kubernetes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="devops">DevOps&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the problem where you can’t view the details of a pipeline.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue with incorrect parameter passing in Jenkins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where graphical shell editing is not effective.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix bug of gc pipelineruns.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of some application resources not being deleted when cascade delete multiple applications.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the failure to set a timeout.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="observability">Observability&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of CPU and memory statistics charts not displaying.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the log receiver page displaying as blank.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="authentication--authorization">Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix LDAP login failure.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="app-store">App Store&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the error that appears on the application repository page.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="other-optimisation">Other Optimisation&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that some components failed to be upgraded.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The full Release Notes can be viewed by visiting the link below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere and Cigo Cloud Partner on Providing Container Services and Building a Developer Community in Africa</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-cigo-partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-cigo-partnership/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ap3.qingstor.com/kubesphere-website/docs/cigo-cloud.png" alt="cigo-and-KubeSphere">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cigo Cloud has committed to providing cloud services and information technologies to enterprises in Africa and beyond. In this spirit of collaboration, KubeSphere and Cigo Cloud are announcing a joint effort to better empower KubeSphere users in Africa on the cloud.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The partnership marks an important milestone as KubeSphere officially provides container services on Cigo Cloud. It was successfully deployed on Johannesburg nodes in September, 2020. On the back of the comprehensive cloud services featuring &amp;quot;cloud-network-edge-end&amp;quot; integration provided by Cigo Cloud, KubeSphere delivers hybrid cloud solutions on top of Kubernetes for users in Africa. This will further promote the adoption of various cloud-native applications across the African continent.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere Announces the Open-Source of Whizard：An Enterprise Distribution of Thanos</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/announcing-whizard-as-open-source/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/announcing-whizard-as-open-source/</guid><description>&lt;p>QingCloud has officially announced the open-source of Whizard, an enterprise distribution of Thanos. This new project provides enterprises with a highly available, scalable, easy-to-maintain, and secure Prometheus long-term storage option, addressing a critical need in the cloud-native ecosystem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Prometheus has become the de facto standard in cloud-native monitoring. However, it falls short in meeting enterprise requirements for high availability, scalability, long-term data storage and query capabilities, ease of operation, and security. Thanos, a leading long-term storage project in the cloud-native community, enhances Prometheus with these capabilities. Despite its advantages, Thanos can be complex to deploy and manage, with numerous components and parameters, making it difficult to use and scale. Additionally, certain components lack horizontal scalability, and security configurations can be cumbersome or inadequate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere Celebrates the Milestone of Reaching 10,000 GitHub Stars</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-10k-stars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-10k-stars/</guid><description>&lt;p>We are celebrating the milestone of reaching 10,000 GitHub stars for our open source project KubeSphere. This moment marks a great achievement on our journey to cloud native distributed OSs!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We want to thank you all, from every contributor, user, to follower for your trust, support, and help for KubeSphere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://openksc.github.io/images/news/kubesphere-10k-stars/kubesphere-10k-stars.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;strong>2018&lt;/strong>, we wrote down the first line of code for the KubeSphere project. Over the past four years, we improved our service nonstop, with more than 10 versions iterated and significant features updated in each major version. This witnessed how we transformed from a startup to an industry influencer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere Enterprise 4.2.0 Is Now Live: Four Major Upgrades Transforming Cloud-Native Operations</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-enterprise-4.2.0-news/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-enterprise-4.2.0-news/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>After three years of dedicated innovation, KubeSphere Enterprise 4.2.0 is officially released!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This release represents a major leap forward in cloud-native management, delivering powerful new features across UI/UX, edge computing, observability, network control, and extensibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="four-core-upgrades-reshaping-the-cloud-native-experience">Four Core Upgrades Reshaping the Cloud-Native Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-brand-new-ui-design-for-unmatched-productivity">1. Brand-New UI Design for Unmatched Productivity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>KubeSphere Enterprise 4.2.0 introduces a modernized user interface to streamline every interaction:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Global Navigation and Sidebar Optimization&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
A new top bar enables seamless perspective switching, while a persistent sidebar offers instant access to key resources with enhanced searchability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere Gateway Component (ingress-nginx) Security Vulnerability Announcement</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-gateway-component-ingress-nginx-security-en/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-gateway-component-ingress-nginx-security-en/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, multiple critical vulnerabilities were discovered in the Ingress-Nginx controller maintained by Kubernetes, including privilege escalation, information disclosure, security bypass, and directory traversal issues. These vulnerabilities affect multiple versions of KubeSphere and KSE. Attackers could exploit these vulnerabilities to execute arbitrary code, access sensitive information, or even fully control the cluster without authorization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given the severity of these vulnerabilities, it is strongly recommended that affected users take immediate action to ensure the security of their clusters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere is Now Available as an AWS Quick Start</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-available-on-aws-quickstart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-available-on-aws-quickstart/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ap3.qingstor.com/kubesphere-website/docs/kubesphere-aws.png" alt="kubesphere-aws">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KubeSphere today announced its expanded relationship with Amazon Web Services (AWS) to offer KubeSphere, a distributed operating system born for managing cloud-native apps across clouds and platforms, as &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/quickstart/architecture/qingcloud-kubesphere/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">an AWS Quick Start&lt;/a>. The Quick Start now allows users to quickly deploy KubeSphere packaged with Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS), providing consistent and streamlined user experiences for both AWS and KubeSphere users as they further grow their Kubernetes footprint on AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere MCP Server: Enhancing AI Integration with KubeSphere</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/ks-mcp-server-2025/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/ks-mcp-server-2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>As cloud-native and AI technologies rapidly converge, the open-source community has been searching for efficient ways to seamlessly integrate AI capabilities into cloud platforms. We are excited to announce that KubeSphere now supports the Model Context Protocol (MCP). With the new KubeSphere MCP Server, users can interact with the KubeSphere API via AI assistants, enabling a smarter cloud management experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-kubesphere-mcp-server">What is KubeSphere MCP Server?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>KubeSphere MCP Server is a service implemented based on the Model Context Protocol (MCP) specification. It enables seamless integration with the KubeSphere API, allowing AI assistants to access and operate on KubeSphere resources. The server consists of four main functional modules:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere Product Lifecycle Policy</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-product-lifecycle-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-product-lifecycle-policy/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Document Versio: v1.0
Last Updated: July 15, 2025&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In a rapidly evolving market, KubeSphere, the product from QingCloud Technologies, has established this Product Lifecycle Policy to ensure that our cloud-native products and services consistently meet customer expectations. By proactively phasing out products that no longer align with market demands, we provide clear termination guidelines, mitigate business risks, and enhance customer trust. Our commitment to technological innovation drives sustainable growth while delivering maximum value to customers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kubesphere Team will join the KubeCon Europe 2022 and bring 3 sessions</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/join-us-at-kubecon-eu-2022/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/join-us-at-kubecon-eu-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://openksc.github.io/images/news/kubecon-eu/kubecon-eu-2022-banner.png" alt="kubecon-eu-banner">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every year, the Cloud-Native Computing Foundation organizes its flagship conference KubeCon and CloudNativeCon, which gathers DevOps, SRE, developers, and technologists to meet leading open source and Cloud-Native communities. This year, KubeCon and CloudNativeCon Europe are just around the corner! KubeSphere Team will bring 3 sessions in KubeCon EU and its co-related event FluentCon in this conference. You can join virtually from 16-20 May 2022.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="session-1-empower-autonomous-driving-with-cloud-native-serverless-technologies">Session 1: Empower Autonomous Driving with Cloud Native Serverless Technologies&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For an Autonomous-Driving platform, the complex use cases and numerous modules pose huge challenges to the entire architecture. Taking data-archiving as an example, large amounts of time-sensitive data are generated in the vehicle and cloud every second, scattering in various devices and clusters. Challenges like multi-types of storage media, non-uniform data size, mixed asynchronous operations, steep resource overhead curves all prompt for a more flexible, elastic, and cost-saving architecture.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere Team will join the KueCon China and bring 5 sessions</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubecon-china-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubecon-china-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every year, the Cloud-Native Computing Foundation organizes its flagship conference KubeCon and CloudNativeCon, which gathers DevOps, SRE, developers, and technologists to meet leading open source and Cloud-Native communities. This year, KubeCon and CloudNativeCon China are coming! KubeSphere Team will bring 4 sessions and participate 1 office hours in this conference, you can join virtually from 9-10 December 2021.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="session-1-kubernetes-multi-cluster-and-multi-tenancy-management-with-rbac-and-kubefed">Session 1: Kubernetes Multi-cluster and Multi-tenancy Management with RBAC and KubeFed&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Soft multi-tenancy is a form of multi-tenancy that does not have strict isolation of the different users, workloads, or applications. When it comes to Kubernetes, soft multi-tenancy is usually isolated by RBAC and namespaces. There are many challenges when cluster administrators implement multi-tenancy across multiple Kubernetes clusters, such as authentication and authorization, resource quota, network policy, security policy, etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere Turkey and Huawei Announce Partnership to Help Enterprises Embrace Cloud Native with Ease</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-turkey-and-huawei-partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-turkey-and-huawei-partnership/</guid><description>&lt;p>KubeSphere, an enterprise-grade container platform for cloud native application management, is ready to expand to global markets. This time, it’s KubeSphere Turkey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On October 18, 2022, KubeSphere Turkey announced partnership with Huawei at HUAWEI CONNECT 2022 PARIS. At this event, KubeSphere Turkey and Huawei reached an agreement that both parties would give full play to their technical and resource advantages to provide Turkish users with localized and quality cloud native services and make joint efforts to empower the new cloud native era.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere v3.3.0 Released: Embrace GitOps</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.3.0-ga-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-3.3.0-ga-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>On June 27, 2022, we are excited to announce the official release of KubeSphere v3.3.0!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The CNCF annual report points out that the dominance of containerization and K8s is becoming secure, and K8s is slowly turning into a background technology: it is everywhere, but not felt by people. This situation benefited from a variety of platforms that make K8s easier to use, among which KubeSphere is one of the leading players. KubeSphere eliminates the complexity and disparity of the underlying K8s cluster for and provides users with an open architecture that supports pluggable components for seamless integration of third-party applications, removing the barriers for enterprises to implement K8s.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere v4 is Released with the New Pluggable Architecture - LuBan</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-v4-ga-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-v4-ga-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>On October 10, 2024, KubeSphere v4 (open source version) is officially released, along with the launch of the brand new pluggable architecture - KubeSphere LuBan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Compared to all previous versions of KubeSphere, KubeSphere v4 represents a revolutionary change. Built on the new cloud-native extensible open architecture - KubeSphere LuBan, KubeSphere v4 serves as a cloud-native operating system that holds extraordinary significance for KubeSphere.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="kubesphere-luban">KubeSphere LuBan&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="what-is-kubesphere-luban">What is KubeSphere LuBan&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>LuBan(鲁班), the ancestor of craftsmen in ancient China, symbolizes the wisdom and creativity of the laboring masses. He improved labor efficiency with tools, liberating workers from primitive and arduous tasks and revolutionizing civil engineering. Named after him, KubeSphere LuBan (KubeSphere Core) aims to offer businesses and developers a cloud-native product with low cost, rapid iteration, and flexible integration, providing a professional, versatile, and creative experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>KubeSphere v4.1.3 Open Source Edition Released</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-4.1.3-ga-announcement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-4.1.3-ga-announcement/</guid><description>&lt;p>KubeSphere 4.1.3 Open Source Edition is officially released, featuring multiple functionality optimizations and bug fixes to further enhance security and usability.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="feature-optimizations">Feature Optimizations&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Optimized the cascading delete logic for enterprise spaces&lt;/strong>
The cascading delete strategy for enterprise spaces has been changed from passive to active to avoid accidental operations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Adjusted authorization rules for platform roles and enterprise space roles&lt;/strong>
Further refined RBAC (Role-Based Access Control) authorization rules to improve security.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Optimized data display on the Pod list page&lt;/strong>
Resource status information is displayed more intuitively, improving usability.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Allow users to associate multiple identity providers&lt;/strong>
Users can now bind multiple identity providers (IdP) at the same time, improving flexibility and compatibility.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Support for manually triggering application repository updates&lt;/strong>
Users can now manually refresh the application repository to ensure the latest application version information is retrieved.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>New “Access Denied” page&lt;/strong>
Invalid page requests are redirected to an &amp;quot;Access Denied&amp;quot; page.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fixed an issue where application instances could not be upgraded.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed compatibility issues with pre-release Kubernetes versions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed configuration issues with LDAP identity providers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed issues where images could not be searched from Docker Hub and Harbor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed issues with handling special characters in application versions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fixed issues preventing the creation of Ingress when the gateway extension is not installed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="installation-and-upgrade">Installation and Upgrade&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We welcome all users to download and experience this release, and provide valuable feedback.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Official Statement on Compliance of Docker Components in KubeSphere</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/docker-components-in-kubesphere-en/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/docker-components-in-kubesphere-en/</guid><description>&lt;p>Beijing QingCloud Technology Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &amp;quot;QingCloud&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;the Company&amp;quot;) adheres to the principles of openness and transparency in cooperation, committed to providing users with secure and compliant cloud-native product solutions. To safeguard user rights and clarify product responsibilities, the Company hereby issues the following official statement regarding the product information and Docker component compliance of the KubeSphere container management platform (hereinafter referred to as &amp;quot;the Platform&amp;quot;):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Radore and KubeSphere: Walk into the Future of Hybrid Cloud and Build Ecosystem Together</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-radore-partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-radore-partnership/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ap3.qingstor.com/kubesphere-website/docs/Radore-KubeSphere-cooperation.jpeg" alt="radore-kubesphere-cooperation">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>June 30, 2020 - In the online launch event of KubeSphere v3.0, Ray Zhou, leader of KubeSphere project, officially announced the exciting news of establishing a strong partnership with Radore, a Turkish enterprise with over 14 years of expertise. The cooperation aims to provide diversified cloud computing solutions for both Turkish companies and individuals, laying a solid foundation for KubeSphere to go global in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ap3.qingstor.com/kubesphere-website/docs/radore-kubesphere-cooperation.png" alt="radore-kubesphere-cooperation">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“In fact, it is Radore that came to us first.” Ray further explained the partnership in detail. “They have done a lot of research and selected KubeSphere in the end. They hope to build a local KubeSphere community and further promote it. They even asked us to authorize them to be the gateway for KubeSphere to Europe and Africa so that more people can share the benefits of KubeSphere.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recap: KubeSphere &amp; Friends 2020 Meetup</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-meetup-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-meetup-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://openksc.github.io/images/news/meetup-2020/Snip20210201_8.png" alt="Snip20210201_8">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Around the latest technology trend – cloud-native, the annual event KubeSphere and Friends 2020, also known as Kubernetes and Cloud-Native Meetup, was held on December 19th, 2020 in Beijing, attracting more than 100 Kubernetes enthusiasts and KubeSphere community members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not only did developers from the KubeSphere team participate in the event, our guests from CNCF and AWS, and other enterprise users all shared their ideas and experiences from different perspectives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spanish and Traditional Chinese Localization Available in KubeSphere Web Console</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/spanish-traditional-chinese-available/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/spanish-traditional-chinese-available/</guid><description>&lt;p>The web console of KubeSphere v3.0 now supports the localization of Spanish and Traditional Chinese. In User Settings, you can select the language of web console in the drop-down menu.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ap3.qingstor.com/kubesphere-website/docs/KubeSphere-language-setting.png" alt="KubeSphere-language-setting">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, we would like to thank &lt;a href="https://geko.cloud/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Geko Cloud&lt;/a>, our Spanish partner that provides the Spanish localization. This serves as a great start for the cooperation between KubeSphere and Geko as the two sides promise to further develop the Spanish community. With a brand-new Spanish web console, KubeSphere aims to create better user experiences for users around the world who prefer Spanish UI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Statement and Solution for KubeSphere IDOR Security Vulnerability CVE-2024-46528</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-cve-2024-46528/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-cve-2024-46528/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, security technicians from a third-party platform discovered a vulnerability of Insecure Direct Object Reference (IDOR) in KubeSphere 3.4.1 and 4.1.1. This vulnerability allows an authenticated attacker with low privileges to access sensitive resources without proper authorization checks. We promptly contacted the other party and helped them solve this problem. For detailed information about the CVE vulnerability and the problem-solving process, please refer to the following links:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2024-46528" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CVE-2024-46528&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://okankurtulus.com.tr/2024/09/09/idor-vulnerability-in-kubesphere/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">IDOR Vulnerability in KubeSphere&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="affected-versions">Affected Versions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>KubeSphere 4.x: &amp;lt; 4.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>KubeSphere 3.x: &amp;gt;= 3.0.0, &amp;lt;= 3.4.1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>KubeSphere Enterprise 4.x: &amp;lt; 4.1.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>KubeSphere Enterprise 3.x: &amp;gt;= 3.0.0, &amp;lt;= 3.5.0&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="workaround">Workaround&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Remove the non-essential resource authorization of the &lt;code>authenticated&lt;/code> platform role:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrading KubeSphere from v3.4.x to v4.1.3: Everything You Need to Know</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/how-to-upgrade-kubesphere-from-v3.4.x-to-v4.1.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/how-to-upgrade-kubesphere-from-v3.4.x-to-v4.1.3/</guid><description>&lt;p>This guide provides comprehensive steps for upgrading from KubeSphere v3.4.x to v4.x, helping you complete the upgrade process smoothly. Note: If your KubeSphere version is earlier than v3.4.x, you must first upgrade to v3.4.x before proceeding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The upgrade process consists of the following three major steps. Please execute them in order:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Upgrade the host cluster and migrate extension component data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade the member clusters and migrate extension component data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade the gateway.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="download-the-upgrade-script">Download the Upgrade Script&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Download the upgrade script in both the host and member cluster environments:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome New KubeSphere Ambassadors! KubeSphere Ambassadorship 2023 Applications Announced!</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-ambassador-certificates-20230920/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-ambassador-certificates-20230920/</guid><description>&lt;p>Contributing to the open-source community is not limited to contributing code and documentation and supporting localization and internationalization, but includes technology evangelism as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the KubeSphere Ambassadorship program we organized this year, we received applications from outside for the first time and selected our ambassadors through evaluation. The term of office of our ambassadors will be 1 year, and new ambassador elections can be held at the same time next year. An ambassador can be re-elected as an ambassador every year. Through this ambassador program, we aim to foster a more open community environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome New KubeSphere Ambassadors! Your Exclusive Certificate Is Ready!</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-ambassador-certificates-20220727/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-ambassador-certificates-20220727/</guid><description>&lt;p>Contributing to the open-source community is not limited to contributing code and documentation and supporting localization and internationalization, but includes technology evangelism as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KubeSphere Ambassador is awarded to technical evangelists who are helping to grow the KubeSphere community by writing technical blogs and user cases, sharing technologies in the community, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are happy to announce six new KubeSphere Ambassadors who have contributed in different ways to the KubeSphere community many times to help more users to get to know the application scenarios and best practices of KubeSphere.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome New KubeSphere Contributors! Your Exclusive Certificate Is Ready!</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-contributor-certificates-20220721/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/news/kubesphere-contributor-certificates-20220721/</guid><description>&lt;p>KubeSphere was open sourced in 2018. Thanks to contributions from nearly 300 contributors, KubeSphere has more than 10 releases in four years, with over 10,000 GitHub stars and millions of downloads.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To extend our gratitude to KubeSphere Contributors and encourage more people to get involved with KubeSphere, the KubeSphere community has made Contributor Certificates. Today, we are happy to announce that 101 new KubeSphere Contributors have won the certificates.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-the-certificate">About the Certificate&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>KubeSphere Contributor is awarded to people who have met any of the following criteria:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>