<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Release Notes on</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/</link><description>Recent content in Release Notes on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Release Notes for 4.1.3</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v413/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v413/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="kubesphere">KubeSphere&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements">Enhancements&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Refine the cascading deletion logic for workspace.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adjust the authorization rules for certain platform roles and workspace roles.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimize the data display on the Pod list page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow users to link with multiple identity providers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support manual triggering of application repository updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a &amp;quot;Access Denied&amp;quot; page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adjust the cluster role configuration method in the Helm Chart.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the potential privilege escalation vulnerability in web kubectl.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where the application release cannot be upgraded.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the compatibility issue with the prerelease K8s version number.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the configuration issue with LDAP Identity Provider for LDAPS and STARTTLS.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where images could not be searched from Docker Hub and Harbor.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue with handling special characters in the Application Version.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of unable to create ingress when the gateway extension is not installed.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Release Notes for 4.1.2</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v412/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v412/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="kubesphere">KubeSphere&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Support for OCI-based Helm Chart repositories.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements">Enhancements&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add the default extension repository.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix white screen pages of some extensions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix problem of residual resources when uninstalling ks-core.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix installation failure in K8s 1.19 environments.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="known-issues">Known issues&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The image builder (S2I, B2I) feature in DevOps is not available in this release.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Release Notes for 4.1.1</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v411/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v411/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="kubesphere">KubeSphere&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Refactor based on the new microkernel architecture of KubeSphere LuBan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Introduce the KubeSphere Marketplace as a built-in feature.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for managing extensions through the Extensions Center.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>UI and API can be extended.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for one-click import of member clusters via kubeconfig.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for KubeSphere Service Accounts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for dynamic extension of the Resource API.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for adding clusters, workspaces, and projects to quick access.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enabled file upload and download via container terminal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adapted to cloud-native gateways (Kubernetes Ingress API) from different vendors.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support API rate limiting.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support creating persistent volumes on the page.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements">Enhancements&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Support for selecting all clusters when creating a workspace.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimization of web kubectl, supporting dynamic recycling of pods and fuzzy search when switching clusters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimization of node list, changing the default sorting to ascending order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Only allow trusted OAuth clients to verify user identity directly using username and password.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Streamline the Agent components deployed in member clusters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Split some configurations in KubeSphere Config as independent configuration items.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adjust the search result of container images to sort in reverse chronological order.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for editing user aliases.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Display scheduling status in the cluster list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support binaryData data display in ConfigMap details.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refactor the Workbench page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove unnecessary extensions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support fast deployment and uninstallation via helm.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Simplify the deployment of agents in member clusters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support for disabling terminal for control plane nodes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support triggering cluster resource synchronization proactively.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User experience improvements on the workload pages under clusters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User experience improvements on the application list page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User experience improvements on the persistent volume claim and storage class list pages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimize the display of excessively long resource names.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support globally enabling fieldValidation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support horizontal movement on the cluster nodes list page.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of the node terminal displaying &amp;quot;connecting&amp;quot; indefinitely.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the potential issue of unauthorized access to resources in the workspace.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the potential issue of unauthorized access to cluster authorization APIs in the workspace.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of abnormal session logout due to incorrect configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of exceptions when adding image service information to pull images from a specified repository.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of missing ownerReferences when editing Secrets.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of white screen and incorrect page redirection during the initial login.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the scrolling issue with checkboxes in Windows environment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the problem where the cluster management entry couldn't be found when logged in as cluster-admin.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where closing the kubectl container terminal did not terminate the corresponding pod.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where the cluster cannot be selected when downloading kubeconfig.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where resource names were not fully displayed in some lists due to excessive length.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the missing translations in some pages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the blank display issue on container details page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the default skip certificate verification issue when selecting HTTPS for image registry addresses when creating secrets.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix inability to edit project roles for service accounts of member clusters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix inability to edit settings for configmaps without key-value pairs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix inability to edit or delete key-value pair data for configmaps of member clusters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the display issue with pop-up dialog when removing unready clusters on the cluster management page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the progress bar display issue when removing clusters on cluster management page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix disappearance of the selection status of previously selected clusters after searching for clusters in pop-up dialog for &amp;quot;Add tags to clusters&amp;quot;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix pagination issue for pods on workload details page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix display of HTML comments in changelogs on extension details page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix incomplete display of floating elements on list pages under certain circumstances.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix abnormal display of error messages in the top right corner.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix display issue with pop-up dialog for creating workspaces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix inability to search for Harbor (version 2.8.0 and later) images.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix slow loading of console under HTTPS protocol.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Specify cluster creator as cluster administrator by default.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix exception when deleting labels from nodes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where page does not refresh in real time when adding member clusters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add prompt message when uploading files in containers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where clusters are not filtered based on user permissions when selecting clusters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix potential permission escalation and authorization risks in helm application deployment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where file upload freezes when creating application templates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where applications created in one project are visible in other projects.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where bitnami source in application repository cannot be synchronized.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where application template displays no data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where unauthorized users encounter a blank page when deploying applications from the app store.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix incorrect display of types of secrets.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix display issue with workspace list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix incorrect status in persistent volume list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix failure to create PVC based on snapshots.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove unnecessary prompt for persistent volume expansion.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix incorrect display of type dropdown when creating secrets.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix data filling error when creating secrets with the &amp;quot;Image registry information&amp;quot; type.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where workload list cannot retrieve all projects.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix abnormal display of prompt information for pods in workloads.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where versions displayed in CRDs page is not the latest.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix display issue when searching for clusters in cluster list.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where web kubectl terminal is unusable in EKS environment.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="api-updates">API Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="api-removal">API Removal&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The following APIs will be removed in v4.1:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release Notes for 3.4.1</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v341/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v341/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="app-store">App Store&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the error on the application repository page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the error in the application approval process.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support &amp;quot;select&amp;quot; in Appdeploy schemaform.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="console">Console&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-1">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of losing status when modifying a CRD.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the incorrect style for IsolateInfo and RuleInfo in the Network Policy panel.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix inaccurate Chinese translations on some pages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the resource creation failure issue in higher versions of Kubernetes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue in the dashboard where the names in Recently Access are obscured.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue on the list page where the Customize Columns button displays incomplete content.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the display error of pod status.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue on the PVC page where the capacity selection numbers are displayed incorrectly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue when adding containers on the Create Deployment page, using tags to search for images is not working.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support building ARM64 images.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="multi-cluster">Multi Cluster&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-2">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where CD-related clusters are displayed incorrectly in a multi-cluster environment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of mistakenly adding a host cluster as a member cluster of another cluster.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="observability">Observability&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-3">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that CPU and memory statistics charts are not displaying.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix API call errors on the notification channel page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the blank log receiver page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue on the new notification channel page where conditional filtering values are missing.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="authentication--authorization">Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-4">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix LDAP login failure.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="devops">DevOps&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-5">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where shell is not effective in graphical editing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>When a cluster is not ready or does not install DevOps, DevOps projects are unavailable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the incorrect parameter passing in Jenkins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that clicking the replay button pops up an error prompt.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that the details of a pipeline cannot be viewed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the run error due to the large DevOps pipeline logs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix Jenkins image vulnerability.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that failed to upgrade DevOps to 3.4.0.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the error in the cleanup task.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the failure to set a timeout.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the bug with downloading multi-branch-pipeline artifacts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that disabling discarded history pipelineruns doesn't work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that some application resources are not deleted when cascade deleting multiple applications.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Display the git repo link on the Pipeline page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Improve the API documentation for DevOps.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="user-experience">User Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-6">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue on the Statefuls page where the Pod Grace Period parameter is missing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue where the cluster gateway is not displayed in cluster management.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the error when creating an application route.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add pagination for listing repository tags.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="monitoring">Monitoring&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-7">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that the Monitoring Target field is displayed blank.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For more information about issues and contributors of KubeSphere 3.4.1, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/kubesphere/kubesphere/blob/master/CHANGELOG/CHANGELOG-3.4.1.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release Notes for 3.4.0</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v340/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v340/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="devops">DevOps&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Support user-defined pipeline configuration steps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimize the devops-jenkins JVM memory configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of removing ArgoCD resources without cascade parameters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that downloading artifacts for multi-branch pipelines fails.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that the pipeline running status is inconsistent with Jenkins (Add retry for pipelinerun annotation update).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that the running of a pipeline created by a new user is pending.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="storage">Storage&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-1">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that pvc cannot be deleted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="gateway-and-microservice">Gateway and Microservice&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Gateway supports the configuration of forwarding TCP/UDP traffic.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates-1">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Upgrade ingress nginx: v1.1.0 -&amp;gt; v1.3.1.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade servicemesh:
istio: 1.11.1 -&amp;gt; 1.14.6; kiali: v1.38.1 -&amp;gt; v1.50.1; jaeger: 1.27 -&amp;gt; 1.29.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-2">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that the returned cluster gateways duplicate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the verification error when upgrading the gateway.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the abnormal display of cluster gateway log and resource status after changing gateway namespace configuration.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="observability">Observability&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features-1">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add CRDs such as RuleGroup, ClusterRuleGroup, GlobalRuleGroup to support Alerting v2beta1 APIs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add admission webhook for RuleGroup, ClusterRuleGroup, GlobalRuleGroup.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add controllers to sync RuleGroup, ClusterRuleGroup, GlobalRuleGroup resources to PrometheusRule resources.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add Alerting v2beta1 APIs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The ks-apiserver of Kubesphere integrates the v1 and v2 versions of opensearch, and users can use the external or built-in opensearch cluster for log storage and query. (Currently the built-in opensearch version of Kubesphere is v2).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ks-installer integrates the opensearch dashboard, which should be enabled by users.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates-2">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Upgrade Prometheus stack dependencies.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support configuring the maximum number of logs that can be exported.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The monitoring component supports Kubernetes PDB Apiversion changes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade Notification Manager to v2.3.0.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support cleaning up notification configuration in member clusters when a member cluster is deleted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support switching notification languages.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support route notifications to specified users.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-3">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that Goroutine leaks when getting audit event sender times out.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the promql statement of ingress P95 delay.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="multi-tenancy-and-multi-cluster">Multi-tenancy and Multi-cluster&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates-3">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Check the cluster ID (kube-system UID) when updating the cluster.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-4">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Make sure the cluster is Ready when cleaning up notifications.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the webhook validation issue for new clusters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the incorrect cluster status.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue of potentially duplicated entries for granted clusters in the workspace.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="app-store">App Store&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-5">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the ID generation failure in IPv6-only environment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the missing Home field in app templates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that the uploaded app templates do not show icons.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix missing maintainers in Helm apps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that Helm applications in a failed status cannot be upgraded again.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the wrong &amp;quot;applicationId&amp;quot; parameter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the infinite loop after app installation failure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>FIx the wrong status of application repository.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="network">Network&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates-4">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Upgrade dependencies.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="authentication-and-authorization">Authentication and Authorization&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features-2">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add inmemory cache.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add Resource Getter v1beta1.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add write operation for Resource Manager.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates-5">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add iam.kubesphere/v1beta1 RoleTemplate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update the password minimum length to 8.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update Version API.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update identityProvider API.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add IAM v1beta1 APIs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-6">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that the enableMultiLogin configuration does not take effect.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="api-changes">API Changes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use autoscaling/v2 API.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use batch/v1 API.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Update health check API.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the ks-apiserver crash issue in K8s v1.25.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="user-experience">User Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features-3">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Resource API supports searching alias in annotations.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-7">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix the potential Websocket link leakage issue.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates-6">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Use Helm action package instead of using Helm binary.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adjust the priority of bash and sh in the kubectl terminal.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that ks-apiserver cannot start due to DiscoveryAPI exception.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the issue that the pod status is inconsistent with the filtered status when filtering by status on the pod list page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Support querying the secret list according to the secret type by supporting fieldSelector filtering.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For more information about issues and contributors of KubeSphere 3.4.0, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/kubesphere/kubesphere/blob/master/CHANGELOG/CHANGELOG-3.4.0.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release Notes for 3.3.2</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v332/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v332/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="devops">DevOps&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--upgrades">Enhancements &amp;amp; Upgrades&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add the latest GitHub Actions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Save the PipelineRun results to the configmap.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modify the Chinese description of the status of ArgoCD applications.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add more information to continuous deployment parameters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a link for PipelineRun in the aborted state.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add an ID column for PipelineRun, and the ID will be displayed when users run kubectl commands.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the queued state from PipelineRun.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where webhook configurations are missing after users change and save pipeline configurations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where downloading DevOps pipeline artifacts fails.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where the image address does not match when a service is created by using a JAR/WAR file.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where the status of PipelineRun changes from &lt;code>Cancelled&lt;/code> to &lt;code>Not-Running&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix the automatic cleaning behavior of pipelines to keep it consistent with the cleaning configurations of Jenkins.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="app-store">App Store&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-1">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where the application icon is not displayed on the uploaded application template.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where the homepage of an application is not displayed on the application information page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where importing built-in applications fails.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix a UUID generation error in an IPv6-only environment.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="observability">Observability&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-2">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix a parsing error in the configuration file of logsidecar-injector.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="service-mesh">Service Mesh&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-3">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix an issue that application governance of Bookinfo projects without service mesh enabled is not disabled by default.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where the delete button is missing on the blue-green deployment details page.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="network">Network&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-4">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Restrict network isolation of projects within the current workspace.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="storage">Storage&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--upgrades-1">Enhancements &amp;amp; Upgrades&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Display the cluster to which system-workspace belongs in multi-cluster environments.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Rename route to ingress.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="authentication--authorization">Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--upgrades-2">Enhancements &amp;amp; Upgrades&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add dynamic options for cache.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the &amp;quot;Alerting Message Management&amp;quot; permission.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-5">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where platform roles with platform management permisions cannot manage clusters.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="development--testing">Development &amp;amp; Testing&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-6">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where some data is in the &lt;code>Out of sync&lt;/code> state after the live-reload feature is introduced.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where the ks-apiserver fails when it is reloaded multiple times.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where caching resources fails if some required CRDs are missing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where the ks-apiserver crashes in Kubernetes 1.24+ versions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where Goroutine leaks occur when the audit event sender times out.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="user-experience">User Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Limit the length of cluster names.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where pod replicas of a federated service are not automatically refreshed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where related pods are not deleted after users delete a service.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where the number of nodes and roles are incorrectly displayed when there is only one node.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For more information about issues and contributors of KubeSphere 3.3.2, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/kubesphere/kubesphere/blob/master/CHANGELOG/CHANGELOG-3.3.2.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release Notes for 3.3.1</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v331/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v331/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="devops">DevOps&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add support for editing the kubeconfig binding mode on the pipeline UI.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where users fail to check the CI/CD template.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the &lt;code>Deprecated&lt;/code> tag from the CI/CD template and replace &lt;code>kubernetesDeploy&lt;/code> with &lt;code>kubeconfig binding&lt;/code> at the deployment phase.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="network">Network&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-1">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where users fail to create routing rules in IPv6 and IPv4 dual-stack environments.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="storage">Storage&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-2">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Set &lt;code>hostpath&lt;/code> as a required option when users are mounting volumes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="authentication--authorization">Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-3">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Delete roles &lt;code>users-manager&lt;/code> and &lt;code>workspace-manager&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add role &lt;code>platform-self-provisioner&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Block some permissions of custom roles.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="user-experience">User Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add support for changing the number of items displayed on each page of a table.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add support for batch stopping workloads.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For more information about issues and contributors of KubeSphere 3.3.1, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/kubesphere/kubesphere/blob/master/CHANGELOG/CHANGELOG-3.3.1.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release Notes for 3.3.0</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v330/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v4.1/20-release-notes/release-v330/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="devops">DevOps&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add the Continuous Deployment feature, which supports GitOps and uses Argo CD as the backend, and users can view the status of continuous deployments in real time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the allowlist feature on the &lt;strong>Basic Information&lt;/strong> page of a DevOps project to restrict the target repository and deployment location for continuous deployments.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add support for importing and managing code repositories.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add support for built-in CRD-based pipeline templates and parameter customization.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add support for viewing pipeline events.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="storage">Storage&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features-1">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add support for tenant-level storage class permission management.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the volume snapshot content management and volume snapshot class management features.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add support for automatic restart of deployments and statefulsets after a PVC has been changed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the PVC auto expansion feature, which automatically expands PVCs when remaining capacity is insufficient.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="multi-tenancy-and-multi-cluster">Multi-tenancy and Multi-cluster&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features-2">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add a notification to remind users when the kubeconfig certificate of a cluster is about to expire.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the kubesphere-config configmap, which provides the name of the current cluster.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add support for cluster-level member and role management.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="observability">Observability&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features-3">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add process and thread monitoring metrics for containers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add disk monitoring metrics that provide usage of each disk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add support for importing Grafana templates to create custom monitoring dashboards of a namespace scope.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add support for defining separate data retention periods for container logs, resource events, and audit logs.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Upgrade Alertmanager from v0.21.0 to v0.23.0.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade Grafana from 7.4.3 to 8.3.3.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade kube-state-metrics from v1.9.7 to v2.3.0.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade node-exporter from v0.18.1 to v1.3.1.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade Prometheus from v2.26.0 to v2.34.0.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade Prometheus Operator from v0.43.2 to v0.55.1.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade kube-rbac-proxy from v0.8.0 to v0.11.0.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade configmap-reload from v0.3.0 to v0.5.0.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade Thanos from v0.18.0 to v0.25.2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade kube-events from v0.3.0 to v0.4.0.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade Fluent Bit Operator from v0.11.0 to v0.13.0.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Upgrade Fluent Bit from v1.8.3 to v1.8.11.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="kubeedge-integration">KubeEdge Integration&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features-4">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add support for logging in to common cluster nodes and edge nodes from the KubeSphere web console.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates-1">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Upgrade KubeEdge from v1.7.2 to v1.9.2.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove EdgeWatcher.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="network">Network&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="enhancements--updates-2">Enhancements &amp;amp; Updates&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Integrate OpenELB with KubeSphere for exposing LoadBalancer services.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where the gateway of a project is not deleted after the project is deleted.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="app-store">App Store&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="bug-fixes-1">Bug Fixes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Fix a ks-controller-manager crash caused by Helm controller NPE errors.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="authentication--authorization">Authentication &amp;amp; Authorization&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="features-5">Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add support for manually disabling and enabling users.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="user-experience">User Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Add a prompt when the audit log of Kubernetes has been enabled.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the lifecycle management feature for containers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add support for creating container environment variables in batches from secrets and configmaps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a time range selector on the &lt;strong>Traffic Monitoring&lt;/strong> tab page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add a message in the &lt;strong>Audit Log Search&lt;/strong> dialog, which prompts users to enable the audit logs feature.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add more Istio parameters in &lt;code>ClusterConfiguration&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add support for more languages, for example, Turkish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set the &lt;strong>Token&lt;/strong> parameter on the webhook settings page as mandatory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prevent passwords without uppercase letters set through the backend CLI.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where no data is displayed on the &lt;strong>Traffic Management&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Tracing&lt;/strong> tab pages in a multi-cluster project.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an app installation failure, which occurs when users click buttons too fast.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where container probes are still displayed after they are deleted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fix an issue where statefulset creation fails when a volume is mounted to an init container.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Prevent ks-apiserver and ks-controller-manager from restarting when the cluster configuration is changed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimize some UI texts.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Optimize display of the service topology on the &lt;strong>Service&lt;/strong> page.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>For more information about issues and contributors of KubeSphere 3.3.0, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/kubesphere/kubesphere/blob/master/CHANGELOG/CHANGELOG-3.3.md" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>