<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Toolbox on</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/toolbox/</link><description>Recent content in Toolbox on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/toolbox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Log Query</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/toolbox/log-query/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/toolbox/log-query/</guid><description>&lt;p>The logs of applications and systems can help you better understand what is happening inside your cluster and workloads. The logs are particularly useful for debugging problems and monitoring cluster activities. KubeSphere provides a powerful and easy-to-use logging system which offers users the capabilities of log collection, query and management from the perspective of tenants. The tenant-based logging system is much more useful than Kibana since different tenants can only view their own logs, leading to better security. Moreover, the KubeSphere logging system filters out some redundant information so that tenants can only focus on logs that are useful to them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Event Query</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/toolbox/events-query/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/toolbox/events-query/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kubernetes events provide insight into what is happening inside a cluster, based on which KubeSphere adds longer historical query and aggregation capabilities, and also supports event query for tenant isolation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This guide demonstrates how you can do multi-level, fine-grained event queries to track the status of your components.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../../pluggable-components/events/">KubeSphere Events&lt;/a> needs to be enabled.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="query-events">Query Events&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The event query function is available for all users. Log in to the console with any account, hover over &lt;img src="https://openksc.github.io/images/docs/v3.x/toolbox/event-query/toolbox.png" width='20' alt="icon" /> in the lower-right corner and select &lt;strong>Resource Event Search&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web Kubectl</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/toolbox/web-kubectl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.3/toolbox/web-kubectl/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Kubernetes command-line tool, kubectl, allows you to run commands on Kubernetes clusters. You can use kubectl to deploy applications, inspect and manage cluster resources, view logs, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>KubeSphere provides web kubectl on the console for user convenience. By default, in the current version, only the account granted the &lt;code>platform-admin&lt;/code> role (such as the default account &lt;code>admin&lt;/code>) has the permission to use web kubectl for cluster resource operation and management.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>