<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Multi-cluster Management on</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.4/faq/multi-cluster-management/</link><description>Recent content in Multi-cluster Management on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.4/faq/multi-cluster-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manage a Multi-cluster Environment on KubeSphere</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.4/faq/multi-cluster-management/manage-multi-cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.4/faq/multi-cluster-management/manage-multi-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p>KubeSphere provides an easy-to-use multi-cluster feature to help you &lt;a href="../../../multicluster-management/">build your multi-cluster environment on KubeSphere&lt;/a>. This guide illustrates how to manage a multi-cluster environment on KubeSphere.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure your Kubernetes clusters are installed with KubeSphere before you use them as your Host Cluster and Member Clusters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure the cluster role is set correctly on your Host Cluster and Member Clusters respectively, and the &lt;code>jwtSecret&lt;/code> is the same between them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Restore the Host Cluster Access to A Member Cluster</title><link>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.4/faq/multi-cluster-management/host-cluster-access-member-cluster/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openksc.github.io/docs/v3.4/faq/multi-cluster-management/host-cluster-access-member-cluster/</guid><description>&lt;p>KubeSphere features &lt;a href="../../../multicluster-management/introduction/kubefed-in-kubesphere/">multi-cluster maganement&lt;/a> and tenants with necessary permissions (usually cluster administrators) can access the central control plane from the Host Cluster to manage all the Member Clusters. It is highly recommended that you manage your resources across your cluster through the Host Cluster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This tutorial demomstrates how to restore the Host Cluster access to a Member Cluster.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="possible-error-message">Possible Error Message&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you can't access a Member Cluster from the central control plane and your browser keeps redirecting you to the login page of KubeSphere, run the following command on that Member Cluster to get the logs of the ks-apiserver.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>